<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kathy.life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kathy.life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-07-21T22:51:57+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kathy’s Blog</title><subtitle>Life is too short to build boring things.</subtitle><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><entry><title type="html">Life is Too Short to Build Boring Things</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/07/21/life-is-too-short-to-build-boring-things.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Life is Too Short to Build Boring Things" /><published>2019-07-21T22:43:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-07-21T22:43:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/07/21/life-is-too-short-to-build-boring-things</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/07/21/life-is-too-short-to-build-boring-things.html">&lt;p&gt;I have updated the About section of my website a little bit. It now includes some of the questions that I constantly ask myself and reflect upon:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you bored by what you do on a daily basis? Can the boring tasks be handled by robots instead? Can &lt;em&gt;YOU&lt;/em&gt; contribute to the design of new robots? What are your ethical guidelines?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are you uniquely qualified to do? Are you doing what you are uniquely qualified to do? If not, why not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you proud of what you do? Will you still be proud of what you do 10 years from now? What about 50 years from now?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are your dreams? Are there any steps you can start taking today to get closer to those dreams? If you don’t start taking the steps, will you regret it 10 years later? What about 50 years later?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">I have updated the About section of my website a little bit. It now includes some of the questions that I constantly ask myself and reflect upon:</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to My New Blog</title><link href="https://kathy.life/news/2019/07/14/welcome-to-my-new-blog.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to My New Blog" /><published>2019-07-14T18:05:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-07-14T18:05:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/news/2019/07/14/welcome-to-my-new-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/news/2019/07/14/welcome-to-my-new-blog.html">&lt;p&gt;In the past 3 years or so, I have been fortunate enough to garner a humble readership on Medium, publishing both technical and non-technical posts alike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As pleasant to use as Medium has been, I have decided to once again move to a self-hosted blog. That way I get to retain control of the content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This new blog is primarily built with free tools. More specifically, I use Jekyll as the static site generator. The resulting site is hosted on GitHub Pages. The only thing I have to pay for is the domain name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hoping that this will become a consolidated place for all of my ramblings. So future Medium-worthy articles will most likely land here. I may also choose to publish some status updates here instead of up on social media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not meant to be a social media cleanse, per se. I just quite like the idea of having a central, self-hosted means of content consolidation.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">In the past 3 years or so, I have been fortunate enough to garner a humble readership on Medium, publishing both technical and non-technical posts alike.</summary></entry></feed>