<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kathy.life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kathy.life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-03-27T22:11:04+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kathy’s Blog</title><subtitle>Life is too short to build boring things.</subtitle><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><entry><title type="html">How to Hook Up Custom Domain Emails to Free Gmail Account</title><link href="https://kathy.life/final-static/set-up-custom-domain-emails-free/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How to Hook Up Custom Domain Emails to Free Gmail Account" /><published>2022-03-26T17:18:21+08:00</published><updated>2022-03-26T17:18:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/final-static/set-up-custom-domain-emails-free</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/final-static/set-up-custom-domain-emails-free/">&lt;p&gt;In the previous blog post, I had signed up for a free Gmail account to manage emails for the Final Static project. As a follow-up, I am going to document the steps I took to connect it with the custom domain I had newly purchased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Under this setup, I would essentially enjoy all the free services that come with a Gmail account (including 15 GB of cloud storage), while having a professional customer-facing email address that ends with the custom domain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if you happen to be in a similar situation with your project, this documentation will hopefully serve as a helpful tutorial for you as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-not-just-use-google-workspace&quot;&gt;Why not just use Google Workspace?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason is to cut down on recurring costs, at least at the early stages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, a Google Workspace (formerly G Suite) Business Starter plan will indeed allow you to create a custom business email and get 30 GB cloud storage per user (at the time of this post).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plus, once you have signed up for a Workspace account, you will have the option to create email “aliases” — which will be useful for setting up several different identities / message filters for your brand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And for the sake of full disclosure, I do use Google Workspace for my *main* company email addresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, if you are like me and actively run a ton of pet projects, those Workspace plan fees will add up…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s say you have 20 standalone projects that each uses its own domain. Even just the basic Workspace fees would come out to be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$6.00 / user / month x 12 months x 20 projects = $1,440 per year&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Versus…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cost of this setup = $0&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will only need to pay the domain fee on an annual basis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Side note: And given that this new project is about NFTs, I thought it’s also worth mentioning that NFT domains — which you would pay once and own forever — may soon become more common, and thus further eliminating the recurring fees to “rent” web2 domains. Perhaps more on that in a future post.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-goals-of-my-setup&quot;&gt;The goals of my setup&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was trying to achieve:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get a &lt;strong&gt;custom domain name&lt;/strong&gt; (finalstatic.io) for an annual subscription fee from Google Domains&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Sign up for a &lt;strong&gt;free Gmail account&lt;/strong&gt; to use with the project (finalstatic.io@gmail.com)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set up a &lt;strong&gt;custom domain email address for free&lt;/strong&gt; (hello@finalstatic.com) via Google Domains, making use of the purchased custom domain&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Have emails that are sent to the custom domain email (hello@finalstatic.io) automatically &lt;strong&gt;forwarded to the Gmail account&lt;/strong&gt; (finalstatic.io@gmail.com)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send email as&lt;/strong&gt; hello@finalstatic.io&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Eliminate the need to purchase a new Google Workspace account for every new project&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make the most of all the free Google services that come with the Gmail account&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;now-the-step-by-step-guide&quot;&gt;Now, the step-by-step guide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. Sign up for a free Gmail account. In my case, it’s finalstatic.io@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_01-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. Purchase a custom domain for your project from Google Domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/23/final-static_google-domains.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. From Google Domains, set up Email Forwarding: Click on &lt;strong&gt;Add email alias&lt;/strong&gt; under the Email tab &amp;gt; type in the alias you want &amp;gt; enter the existing email you want to forward to &amp;gt; click the &lt;strong&gt;Add&lt;/strong&gt; button&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_03-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my case, I’m trying to have messages sent to hello@finalstatic.io forwarded to my Gmail, finalstatic.io@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The * symbol acts as a wildcard here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_03-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_03-c.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. Confirm your existing email (check your Gmail inbox for the message).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_04-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;At this point, you are pretty much good to go!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All emails sent to finalstatic.io can now be found in the Gmail inbox of finalstatic.io@gmail.com.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Simple as that!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;optional&quot;&gt;[Optional]&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;But what if you want to be able to “send” or “reply to” emails from your custom email address?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are probably aware that with this setup, you don’t actually “send”” and “receive” emails with your custom email (hello@finalstatic.io for me).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You don’t really touch an inbox or other folders of the custom email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But thanks to the magic of email forwarding and Gmail alias, you will be able to act as if you are doing just that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-steps-to-set-up-the-sending-from-part&quot;&gt;Additional steps to set up the “sending from” part:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Part I.&lt;/strong&gt; Set up an App Password for your Gmail account to allow you to use the Gmail SMTP servers securely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. Go to the Gmail account. Click on your user icon in the upper right corner to bring up the user menu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;6. Click &lt;strong&gt;Manage your Google Account&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_06-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7. In the Google Account screen, click on the &lt;strong&gt;Security&lt;/strong&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_07-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;8. In the &lt;strong&gt;Signing in to Google&lt;/strong&gt; section, click on the &lt;strong&gt;App passwords&lt;/strong&gt; bar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may be asked to re-enter your password at this point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_08-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note:&lt;/strong&gt; You must have &lt;strong&gt;2-Step Verification&lt;/strong&gt; enabled for the App passwords option to be available. If it is not, click on &lt;strong&gt;2-Step Verification&lt;/strong&gt; and follow the steps to enable 2-Step Verification. Then continue to set the App password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_08-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_08-c.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9. In the App passwords box, select &lt;strong&gt;Mail&lt;/strong&gt; for the app, select &lt;strong&gt;Other&lt;/strong&gt; for the device.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_09-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;10. Enter the name of your domain for the “other” device, and click Generate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_10-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11. The Generated app password box will display a 16-character password. Copy this password. You will need it when you add your new send-as (forwarded) account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_11-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;12. Return to your Gmail screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part II.&lt;/strong&gt; Add the alias as an account to your Gmail inbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;13. In the top right corner, click the &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_13-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;14. Click the &lt;strong&gt;See all settings&lt;/strong&gt; button.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;15. In the &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt; screen, click the &lt;strong&gt;Accounts and Import&lt;/strong&gt; tab.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;16. Scroll down to &lt;strong&gt;Send mail as&lt;/strong&gt; and click &lt;strong&gt;Add another email address&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_16-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;17. In the first &lt;strong&gt;Add another email address&lt;/strong&gt; box, enter the name you want recipients of your email to see (such as “Support Team” or “Sales” or any other name for this contact) and the forwarded email address you are setting up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_17-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;18. Click &lt;strong&gt;Next Step&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Part III.&lt;/strong&gt; Set the Gmail SMTP server as the mail server for your forwarded alias, using the generated App Password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;19. In the second &lt;strong&gt;Add another email address&lt;/strong&gt; box, change the values in fields to enter the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SMTP Server:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;smtp.gmail.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Port:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;465&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Username:&lt;/strong&gt; Your Gmail account (the one you are logged in as)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Password:&lt;/strong&gt; The generated app password you copied in Step 11.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_19-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;20. Click &lt;strong&gt;Add Account&lt;/strong&gt;. If you see an error message, check to make sure you have entered the SMTP server, Port, Username, and Password correctly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;21. After you have successfully added the account, return to Gmail. You will see a message from &lt;strong&gt;Gmail Team&lt;/strong&gt; with the subject &lt;strong&gt;Gmail Confirmation: Send Mail As&lt;/strong&gt; and the address you have just added. Follow the instructions in the message to confirm the email address.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_21-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_21-b.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;22. When you send mail from your Gmail account, click the triangle next to your &lt;strong&gt;From&lt;/strong&gt; address to choose to send the message from the account you just added.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/26/final-static_custom-emails_22-a.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s it!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">As things stand, the first edition of this guide has been one of my most viewed Medium articles thus far.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">If You Name It</title><link href="https://kathy.life/final-static/if-you-name-it/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="If You Name It" /><published>2022-03-23T17:33:21+08:00</published><updated>2022-03-23T17:33:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/final-static/if-you-name-it</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/final-static/if-you-name-it/">&lt;p&gt;When we give our pet project a name and identity, we become that much more attached to it and, in turn, may just have a higher likelihood of seeing it through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-new-project&quot;&gt;The New Project&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier in the month I got an idea to start “Project NFT Inception” — a project where I would code up an NFT marketplace for code, which would then sell its own source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An idea, of course, doesn’t mean much if there’s no action to back it up. That’s why  the plan is to start building out the prototype as soon as I can. To make the most out of the experience, I am also going to be documenting the entire process every step of the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you are reading now is essentially the first post of this dedicated blog series by the same moniker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-name&quot;&gt;The Name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you may have guessed, “Project NFT Inception” is really just a code name. Not too long after coming up with the project idea, I was really stoked to have then thought of an official brand name that I was honestly quite fond of. Ladies and gentlemen, may I present to you, “Final Static.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a fellow developer who has a good grasp of Java, you’ll probably immediately get the meaning behind this name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But if it isn’t obvious to you, no worries. I’ll break it down below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-its-a-fitting-name&quot;&gt;Why It’s a Fitting Name&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-java&quot; data-lang=&quot;java&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;final&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;static&lt;/span&gt; &lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;final&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; are both keywords in the Java language. A combination of the two keywords (either &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;final static&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;static final&lt;/code&gt;) is normally used to define constants in Java. Individually, they each have their own meaning as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a field is marked &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;final&lt;/code&gt;, its value is permanent and can’t be modified once assigned.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is somewhat analogous to how items like smart contracts on the blockchain are immutable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;static&lt;/code&gt; field means there is ever only one single copy (in other words, just the original) of it. When a field is declared &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;static&lt;/code&gt;, it remains the same for every instance of the class, and at the same time can also be accessed by pretty much any other classes — without its class object needing to be instantiated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In essence, this is very much like how NFT works. While anyone can technically access and download the digital assets, there is ever only one authentic ownership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The only-ness and permanence are why I thought “Final Static” would make a great name for an NFT marketplace, given NFT’s nature. In addition, the fact that it is a combination of commonly used programming keywords makes the name all the more appropriate for a marketplace dedicated specifically to computer code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, the two Java keywords have some additional characteristics too. But for the sake of explaining the brand name adoption, I am only listing the ones that draw similarities with NFT source code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;claim-the-domain&quot;&gt;Claim the Domain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the name locked down, it’s time to purchase a domain name. This part was a no-brainer. I basically just went with one of my usual registrars, Google Domains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/23/final-static_google-domains.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speaking of which, if you are reading this post shortly after it’s published, I think I may have a nice surprise for you. Apparently Google Domains has recently moved out of Beta, and I got a celebratory email update from them that came with a discount code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I ought to make it clear that this is not an ad for Google Domains, nor is this post affiliated with them. I am merely including the discount code in case you happened to find it useful. So here goes. In the email it says:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;h3 id=&quot;invite-your-friends&quot;&gt;Invite your friends&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Have a friend who hasn’t tried Google Domains yet? New users can enter code &lt;strong&gt;FRIENDSOFDOMAINS&lt;/strong&gt; at checkout for 25% off** a new domain or transfer﻿-﻿in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-logo&quot;&gt;The Logo&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to brand identities, I normally don’t make it a priority to have the “perfect” logo in place. In fact, in almost all past projects, I would just scribble up the first editions myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s one I made for Final Static in Photoshop:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/03/23/final-static_photoshop-logo.png&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-email&quot;&gt;The Email&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a name at my disposal really helps smoothen the process of getting the wheels rolling. Almost equally important would be an email address. For that purpose, I went on to sign up for a free Gmail account to use for the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the next post, I will go over what I did to hook up the custom domain emails with this new Gmail account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;**Google Domains Out of Beta Refer-a-Friend Discount Terms &amp;amp; Conditions&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;Valid for 25% discount, with a maximum redemption value of $10 USD (or the local currency equivalent), against a new or transfer in domain registration price from eligible top level domains on Google Domains. Discount pricing valid for the initial purchase term for a single domain registration only. Renewal pricing subject to change. Limit one discount per domain name registration per customer. Google reserves the right to cancel, suspend or modify part of this offer at any time without notice, for any reason in its sole discretion. Promotional code must be automatically or manually applied, is non-transferable and has no cash value. To redeem the offer, you must have or activate a Google account. Offer ends March 29, 2022 or while supplies last.&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Then it's all official.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Street Signs</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/street-signs/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Street Signs" /><published>2022-01-28T05:33:21+08:00</published><updated>2022-01-28T05:33:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/street-signs</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/street-signs/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/2022/01/28/street_signs.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-center&quot; class=&quot;align-center&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;small&gt;[Kingston Street, Causeway Bay, 2022]&lt;/small&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The street signs in Hong Kong — as compact as they tend to be in size — subtly pack a lot of useful information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take this one in the picture. The straight edge on the left of the sign tells us that there is no more building further down the left, indicating that the street begins right there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, the pointy edge on the right says there are more buildings or dwellings toward that direction. More specifically, #9 to #11, as printed on the sign as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One could then speculate that the opposite side of the street (where I was standing at the time) houses the even-numbered premises. That is exactly the case here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Source: My own observation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camera: Rollei 35 S&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Film: Fujifilm Superia X-TRA 400 (expired in April, 2018)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">The street signs in Hong Kong — as compact as they tend to be in size — subtly pack a lot of useful information.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Milkweed</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/milkweed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Milkweed" /><published>2021-10-12T03:33:21+08:00</published><updated>2021-10-12T03:33:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/milkweed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/milkweed/">&lt;p&gt;Most milkweed flowers are poisonous to humans and pets, but at the same time can be a great nectar source for pollinators like butterflies and honeybees — *if* they don’t get trapped inside and die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be yourself, and the right people will come by at some point or another. Those who are not meant to be in your life are simply that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Most milkweed flowers are poisonous to humans and pets, but at the same time can be a great nectar source for pollinators like butterflies and honeybees — *if* they don’t get trapped inside and die.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exit</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/exit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exit" /><published>2021-09-10T23:03:21+08:00</published><updated>2021-09-10T23:03:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/exit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/exit/">&lt;p&gt;Getting a rejection is like taking an early exit on the freeway. You are not necessarily changing your destination; perhaps you are just taking a different route to get there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Getting a rejection is like taking an early exit on the freeway. You are not necessarily changing your destination; perhaps you are just taking a different route to get there.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">History</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/history/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History" /><published>2020-12-13T03:33:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T03:33:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/history</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/history/">&lt;p&gt;History has repeatedly told us not to repeat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been historically terrible at learning from what history tells us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">History has repeatedly told us not to repeat it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Respect</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/respect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Respect" /><published>2020-11-10T01:57:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-11-10T01:57:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/respect</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/respect/">&lt;p&gt;Part of my ethos is to treat everyone respectfully, regardless of whether or not they are successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tremendously more respect for people who:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; have fought against hardships throughout their lives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; have overcome personal struggles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; have the audacity to take responsibility for past mistakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; set goals, failed (perhaps even more than once), and stood back up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 46th U.S. President-elect is one example of all of the above.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Part of my ethos is to treat everyone respectfully, regardless of whether or not they are successful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prototyping Paradigm Shift</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/prototyping-paradigm-shift/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prototyping Paradigm Shift" /><published>2020-04-07T01:55:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T01:55:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/prototyping-paradigm-shift</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/prototyping-paradigm-shift/">&lt;p&gt;As someone who is actively developing a series of solutions to help fight against COVID-19, I think it’s safe to say that the global crisis presents a paradigm shift in the way we prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amidst the pandemic, the questions we should now be asking ourselves are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. First and foremost, how fast can the solution be deployed? What corners can be safely cut in order to launch the first version even quicker?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, it’s not unlike creating a minimum viable product (MVP) in pre-COVID times. However, there is less tolerance for error in what we choose to release now. Also, effectiveness should come before aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. What materials or resources are required for deployment? Would reliance on them lead to a new wave of shortages? And if so, are there any feasible alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. How many people can benefit from the solution? If there is potential to boost that number now or in the future, then excellent! Ultimately though, helping *someone* is better than helping *no one*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, avoid dwelling on this question for too long. Go ahead and implement your prototype even if it will only be helpful to a small group of people at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. How well will the solution scale? Is there room for expansions or even spin-offs when this is all over? If so, great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like #3 though, go ahead regardless. After all, the priority here is to defeat the pandemic. Besides, just as in normal times, a product for everyone is a product for no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. What are some financing options? Whilst I don’t recommend profiting off of commercializing anti-COVID solutions, there are quite a few funding streams that will help accelerate the realization of your social missions. (Just watch out for scams.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">As someone who is actively developing a series of solutions to help fight against COVID-19, I think it’s safe to say that the global crisis presents a paradigm shift in the way we prototype.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drones</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/drones/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drones" /><published>2020-03-25T04:04:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T04:04:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/drones</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/drones/">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we are like drones. Bringing others down won’t make you fly higher.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Sometimes we are like drones. Bringing others down won’t make you fly higher.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Level Up</title><link href="https://kathy.life/blog/level-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Level Up" /><published>2020-03-25T02:55:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T02:55:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/blog/level-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/blog/level-up/">&lt;p&gt;We will have leveled up when this is all over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s more than just an involuntary lockdown. Think of this period of trying times as a secret training camp — from which we will emerge stronger, more intelligent, more compassionate, and with slightly longer hair.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">We will have leveled up when this is all over.</summary></entry></feed>