<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kathy.life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kathy.life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-12T22:08:39+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kathy’s Blog</title><subtitle>Life is too short to build boring things.</subtitle><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><entry><title type="html">Milkweed</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2021/10/12/milkweed/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Milkweed" /><published>2021-10-12T03:33:21+08:00</published><updated>2021-10-12T03:33:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2021/10/12/milkweed</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2021/10/12/milkweed/">&lt;p&gt;Most milkweed flowers are poisonous to humans and pets, but at the same time can be a great nectar source for pollinators like butterflies and honeybees — *if* they don’t get trapped inside and die.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be yourself, and the right people will come by at some point or another. Those who are not meant to be in your life are simply that.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Most milkweed flowers are poisonous to humans and pets, but at the same time can be a great nectar source for pollinators like butterflies and honeybees — *if* they don’t get trapped inside and die.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Exit</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2021/09/10/exit/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exit" /><published>2021-09-10T23:03:21+08:00</published><updated>2021-09-10T23:03:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2021/09/10/exit</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2021/09/10/exit/">&lt;p&gt;Getting a rejection is like taking an early exit on the freeway. You are not necessarily changing your destination; perhaps you are just taking a different route to get there.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Getting a rejection is like taking an early exit on the freeway. You are not necessarily changing your destination; perhaps you are just taking a different route to get there.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">History</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/12/13/history/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="History" /><published>2020-12-13T03:33:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-12-13T03:33:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/12/13/history</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/12/13/history/">&lt;p&gt;History has repeatedly told us not to repeat it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We have been historically terrible at learning from what history tells us.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">History has repeatedly told us not to repeat it.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Respect</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/11/10/respect/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Respect" /><published>2020-11-10T01:57:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-11-10T01:57:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/11/10/respect</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/11/10/respect/">&lt;p&gt;Part of my ethos is to treat everyone respectfully, regardless of whether or not they are successful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have tremendously more respect for people who:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt; have fought against hardships throughout their lives&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; have overcome personal struggles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; have the audacity to take responsibility for past mistakes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; set goals, failed (perhaps even more than once), and stood back up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 46th U.S. President-elect is one example of all of the above.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Part of my ethos is to treat everyone respectfully, regardless of whether or not they are successful.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Prototyping Paradigm Shift</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/04/07/prototyping-paradigm-shift/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Prototyping Paradigm Shift" /><published>2020-04-07T01:55:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T01:55:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/04/07/prototyping-paradigm-shift</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/04/07/prototyping-paradigm-shift/">&lt;p&gt;As someone who is actively developing a series of solutions to help fight against COVID-19, I think it’s safe to say that the global crisis presents a paradigm shift in the way we prototype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Amidst the pandemic, the questions we should now be asking ourselves are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1. First and foremost, how fast can the solution be deployed? What corners can be safely cut in order to launch the first version even quicker?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In many ways, it’s not unlike creating a minimum viable product (MVP) in pre-COVID times. However, there is less tolerance for error in what we choose to release now. Also, effectiveness should come before aesthetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2. What materials or resources are required for deployment? Would reliance on them lead to a new wave of shortages? And if so, are there any feasible alternatives?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3. How many people can benefit from the solution? If there is potential to boost that number now or in the future, then excellent! Ultimately though, helping *someone* is better than helping *no one*.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In other words, avoid dwelling on this question for too long. Go ahead and implement your prototype even if it will only be helpful to a small group of people at the beginning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4. How well will the solution scale? Is there room for expansions or even spin-offs when this is all over? If so, great!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like #3 though, go ahead regardless. After all, the priority here is to defeat the pandemic. Besides, just as in normal times, a product for everyone is a product for no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;5. What are some financing options? Whilst I don’t recommend profiting off of commercializing anti-COVID solutions, there are quite a few funding streams that will help accelerate the realization of your social missions. (Just watch out for scams.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">As someone who is actively developing a series of solutions to help fight against COVID-19, I think it’s safe to say that the global crisis presents a paradigm shift in the way we prototype.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Drones</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/drones/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drones" /><published>2020-03-25T04:04:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T04:04:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/drones</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/drones/">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we are like drones. Bringing others down won’t make you fly higher.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Sometimes we are like drones. Bringing others down won’t make you fly higher.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Level Up</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/level-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Level Up" /><published>2020-03-25T02:55:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T02:55:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/level-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/level-up/">&lt;p&gt;We will have leveled up when this is all over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s more than just an involuntary lockdown. Think of this period of trying times as a secret training camp — from which we will emerge stronger, more intelligent, more compassionate, and with slightly longer hair.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">We will have leveled up when this is all over.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Communication Between Someone Blind and Someone Deaf</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/02/17/communication-between-someone-blind-and-someone-deaf/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Communication Between Someone Blind and Someone Deaf" /><published>2020-02-17T10:16:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T10:16:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/02/17/communication-between-someone-blind-and-someone-deaf</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/02/17/communication-between-someone-blind-and-someone-deaf/">&lt;p&gt;Year 2020 has NOT been off to a good start for most of the world, which is why I am now more motivated than ever to squeeze my finite time on Earth to create useful tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am currently working on, is an app that lets a deaf person communicate with a blind person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this is bringing one of my previous apps* a few steps further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open-source, living journals are on their way as we speak. Over the last year, I also made the time to get some channel establishments out of the way, including a podcast and a YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(That’s a lot of breaking out of comfort zone!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just need to remind myself to update the content more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this new app is also being developed in a “side project” fashion, so dev speed is pretty much the last thing I focus on. That being said, we should see at least a demo sometime this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;==========&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*In 2019, I built Listenabel, an interface that reads labels aloud. As a side project, its progress has been slow but steady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that the home stretch is near — for making the app available for public use, including people who happen to be blind or visually impaired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project won’t stop there, though. Nor will I.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Year 2020 has NOT been off to a good start for most of the world, which is why I am now more motivated than ever to squeeze my finite time on Earth to create useful tech.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Science Can Only Help So Much</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/01/26/data-science-can-only-help-so-much/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Science Can Only Help So Much" /><published>2020-01-26T18:27:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T18:27:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/01/26/data-science-can-only-help-so-much</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/01/26/data-science-can-only-help-so-much/">&lt;p&gt;Data science is now a lot more mature than it was back in 2003 (the year when the SARS epidemic struck).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understandably, big data is already playing a big role in helping to fight infectious diseases like Ebola and polio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we leverage data science advancements to speed up the eradication of the latest coronavirus outbreak? That sure is giving scientists some food for thought this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, no predictive model — no matter how accurate — is going to keep us from harm’s way if policymakers are not stepping up to take proper measures to protect the people.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Data science is now a lot more mature than it was back in 2003 (the year when the SARS epidemic struck).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Infinite Power</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/09/15/infinite-power/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infinite Power" /><published>2019-09-15T03:52:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T03:52:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/09/15/infinite-power</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/09/15/infinite-power/">&lt;p&gt;Coal, petroleum, natural gas… You probably guessed it: I am naming common examples of finite energy resources — finite being the operative word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once any of these is used up, there will be no way to replenish it. What’s gone is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other end of the renewability spectrum, we have solar energy, wind power, hydropower — just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was thinking about just now though (using my finite, non-renewable time, no less), is a special type of infinite power. Namely, brain-power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a myriad of mind-related resources that we enjoy an abundance of, yet are far too often underutilized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples would be knowledge, creativity, and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge, creativity, and kindness normally never run out, if so chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employing or spreading any of the three won’t reduce its total availability at all. In fact, sharing it with others may even inspire people to go on and generate *more* of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you teach someone something, you don’t lose what you know. There isn’t going to be less for others to learn, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create something, it doesn’t take away what you or others may create in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are kind to someone, it doesn’t reduce your own positive energy at all. Plus, kindness is infectious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an added benefit to consider: Knowledge, creativity, and kindness are major ingredients in coming up with responsible solutions to tackle our resource scarcity problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Coal, petroleum, natural gas… You probably guessed it: I am naming common examples of finite energy resources — finite being the operative word.</summary></entry></feed>