<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://kathy.life/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://kathy.life/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-03-26T03:51:48+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Kathy’s Blog</title><subtitle>Life is too short to build boring things.</subtitle><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><entry><title type="html">Drones</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/drones.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Drones" /><published>2020-03-25T04:04:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T04:04:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/drones</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/drones.html">&lt;p&gt;Sometimes we are like drones. Bringing others down won’t make you fly higher.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Sometimes we are like drones. Bringing others down won’t make you fly higher.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Level Up</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/level-up.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Level Up" /><published>2020-03-25T02:55:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-03-25T02:55:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/level-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/03/25/level-up.html">&lt;p&gt;We will have leveled up when this is all over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s more than just an involuntary lockdown. Think of this period of trying times as a secret training camp — from which we will emerge stronger, more intelligent, more compassionate, and with slightly longer hair.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">We will have leveled up when this is all over.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Communication Between Someone Blind and Someone Deaf</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/02/17/communication-between-someone-blind-and-someone-deaf.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Communication Between Someone Blind and Someone Deaf" /><published>2020-02-17T10:16:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-02-17T10:16:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/02/17/communication-between-someone-blind-and-someone-deaf</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/02/17/communication-between-someone-blind-and-someone-deaf.html">&lt;p&gt;Year 2020 has NOT been off to a good start for most of the world, which is why I am now more motivated than ever to squeeze my finite time on Earth to create useful tech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am currently working on, is an app that lets a deaf person communicate with a blind person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some ways, this is bringing one of my previous apps* a few steps further.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open-source, living journals are on their way as we speak. Over the last year, I also made the time to get some channel establishments out of the way, including a podcast and a YouTube channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(That’s a lot of breaking out of comfort zone!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just need to remind myself to update the content more frequently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now this new app is also being developed in a “side project” fashion, so dev speed is pretty much the last thing I focus on. That being said, we should see at least a demo sometime this year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;==========&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;*In 2019, I built Listenabel, an interface that reads labels aloud. As a side project, its progress has been slow but steady.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am happy to report that the home stretch is near — for making the app available for public use, including people who happen to be blind or visually impaired.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The project won’t stop there, though. Nor will I.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Year 2020 has NOT been off to a good start for most of the world, which is why I am now more motivated than ever to squeeze my finite time on Earth to create useful tech.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Data Science Can Only Help So Much</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2020/01/26/data-science-can-only-help-so-much.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Data Science Can Only Help So Much" /><published>2020-01-26T18:27:21+08:00</published><updated>2020-01-26T18:27:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2020/01/26/data-science-can-only-help-so-much</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2020/01/26/data-science-can-only-help-so-much.html">&lt;p&gt;Data science is now a lot more mature than it was back in 2003 (the year when the SARS epidemic struck).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Understandably, big data is already playing a big role in helping to fight infectious diseases like Ebola and polio.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can we leverage data science advancements to speed up the eradication of the latest coronavirus outbreak? That sure is giving scientists some food for thought this week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That being said, no predictive model — no matter how accurate — is going to keep us from harm’s way if policymakers are not stepping up to take proper measures to protect the people.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Data science is now a lot more mature than it was back in 2003 (the year when the SARS epidemic struck).</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Infinite Power</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/09/15/infinite-power.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Infinite Power" /><published>2019-09-15T03:52:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-09-15T03:52:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/09/15/infinite-power</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/09/15/infinite-power.html">&lt;p&gt;Coal, petroleum, natural gas… You probably guessed it: I am naming common examples of finite energy resources — finite being the operative word.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once any of these is used up, there will be no way to replenish it. What’s gone is gone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other end of the renewability spectrum, we have solar energy, wind power, hydropower — just to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I was thinking about just now though (using my finite, non-renewable time, no less), is a special type of infinite power. Namely, brain-power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a myriad of mind-related resources that we enjoy an abundance of, yet are far too often underutilized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some examples would be knowledge, creativity, and kindness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowledge, creativity, and kindness normally never run out, if so chosen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Employing or spreading any of the three won’t reduce its total availability at all. In fact, sharing it with others may even inspire people to go on and generate *more* of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you teach someone something, you don’t lose what you know. There isn’t going to be less for others to learn, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you create something, it doesn’t take away what you or others may create in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you are kind to someone, it doesn’t reduce your own positive energy at all. Plus, kindness is infectious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s an added benefit to consider: Knowledge, creativity, and kindness are major ingredients in coming up with responsible solutions to tackle our resource scarcity problem.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Coal, petroleum, natural gas… You probably guessed it: I am naming common examples of finite energy resources — finite being the operative word.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Point A to Point B</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/08/31/point-a-to-point-b.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Point A to Point B" /><published>2019-08-31T01:52:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-08-31T01:52:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/08/31/point-a-to-point-b</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/08/31/point-a-to-point-b.html">&lt;p&gt;Just how long is 50 meters?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s not dwell on the “what happened” for now, but I just found myself going down a mind-numbing rabbit hole that is having to untangle a 50m ethernet cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I *had* to think about something else in the meantime to prevent myself from going insane. (Or did that not work at all?)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usain Bolt could sprint across 50 meters in a little over 5 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Phelps could swim across a 50-meter pool in a little over 20 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now what about a 50-meter cable full of knots in the middle? Well, technically, you could make both ends touch each other. In other words, the “travel time” between the two points would be zero seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then the messy knots didn’t go away at all. The cable would still be tangled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course you could always just throw out the tangled cable and get a brand new one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s just that if you didn’t take proper recycling into consideration, you would be producing unjustifiable waste.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, what if you were already halfway through untangling? The longer you waited to take the plunge, the higher your sunk cost (in terms of time) would be.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Just how long is 50 meters?</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Stand Up by Sitting Down</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/08/24/stand-up-by-sitting-down.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Stand Up by Sitting Down" /><published>2019-08-24T04:52:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-08-24T04:52:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/08/24/stand-up-by-sitting-down</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/08/24/stand-up-by-sitting-down.html">&lt;p&gt;I am not a historian, but I read every now and then.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jim Crow laws were a series of American statutes that legalized racial segregation. Existing for about 100 years from as early as 1865 until 1968, the laws were intended to “restore” Southern states to a pre-war class structure by marginalizing African Americans, some of whom were freed slaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Black codes were dictated as a legal way to put black citizens into servitude — taking their voting rights away, controlling where they were allowed to live and work, and how they traveled. The list goes on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Montgomery, Alabama, segregation mandated that the front of a bus be reserved for white residents only, and the seats in the back rows for black residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rosa Parks (1913 - 2005) had had enough. She was tired. No, not physically tired. She said she was tired of giving in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On December 1, 1955, Parks chose to stand up for herself and other African Americans by — interestingly enough — remaining seated. On her commute home from work, the “white” section on the bus was full. The bus driver told Parks to give up her seat in the “colored” section for a white man. Parks refused.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moments later, two police officers approached the bus, arrested Parks and placed her in custody.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On December 5, Parks was found guilty of violating segregation laws in court. She was fined and given a suspended sentence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Her conviction helped initiate the civil rights movement. Black community leaders organized a 381-day bus boycott — led by Dr. Martin Luther King Jr. — during which Parks lost her job and experienced year-long harassment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boycott would only come to an end when the U.S. Supreme Court eventually ruled that bus segregation was unconstitutional.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t all have to be “the mother of the civil rights movement.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But remember this: Every conscious decision we make as a community, everything we did (or didn’t do) collectively on any given day, will inescapably be written into history, forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When future generations look back, some events will seem utterly ridiculous to them, some remarkable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stand up for what you believe is right — even if you are literally sitting down, like Rosa Parks was.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">I am not a historian, but I read every now and then.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Acknowledge Its Existence</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/08/16/acknowledge-its-existence.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Acknowledge Its Existence" /><published>2019-08-16T03:56:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-08-16T03:56:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/08/16/acknowledge-its-existence</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/08/16/acknowledge-its-existence.html">&lt;p&gt;Today’s late-night ramblings are in regard to something that one cannot see, but undoubtedly exists nonetheless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are you thinking what I was thinking? I was going to say — blind spot; or perhaps more than one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take driving. It’s possible that there will be multiple blind spots at any given time, depending upon things like the type of vehicle you are in, your height, your peripheral vision, and many more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Irresponsible drivers risk not only their own life, but that of others who share the road, if they make reckless maneuvers without compensating for blind spots.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compensating for — or even finding ways to completely eliminate — blind spots doesn’t take much time and effort at all, and yet could literally save lives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We just have to be willing to take that step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And in order to be able to act willingly and accordingly, we have to first acknowledge that they are there. We all have blind spots.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">Today’s late-night ramblings are in regard to something that one cannot see, but undoubtedly exists nonetheless.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Likelihood</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/07/31/likelihood.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Likelihood" /><published>2019-07-31T05:04:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-07-31T05:04:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/07/31/likelihood</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/07/31/likelihood.html">&lt;p&gt;I could tell something must have gone wrong. The last stretches of the highway leading up to Tai Lam Tunnel — including the 3.8-kilometer tunnel itself — were brought to a complete standstill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As it turns out, there was a crash involving two double-decker buses, injuring 77 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I ramble on, I’d like to wish everyone who’s injured a speedy recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to be minutes behind the crash. While I was stuck in the heavy traffic with nothing better to do, I couldn’t help but sat there and overthought the situation a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Statistics&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Back in the days of traditional statistics, the mathematical analysis would be something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are the odds of being involved in that accident, out of…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;All the people&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who were headed that direction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Taking that particular means of transportation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At that specific time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;(Plus a whole bunch of other factors)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry, the result isn’t something that’s alarming at all. But at the same time, the ballpark figure also isn’t telling you much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Data Science&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then there is modern-day data science.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How likely is it for someone to be involved in that accident, given:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The number of past accidents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;That occurred in the proximity of the crash site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Around the same time of the day&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a similar model of vehicle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the thing, though. The prediction can range from wildly inaccurate to highly accurate, depending upon various conditions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Has enough data been used? Is the data relevant?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have enough elements been taken into account? Did we forget to consider things like weather, driver’s physical state, materials used, et cetera et cetera?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that is precisely the danger of relying too heavily on half-baked, “data-driven” “A.I.” algorithms in any decision-making process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have shared similar thoughts on these risks in some of my past talks, except with different cases and scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(But now it’s time for me to go to bed and stop overthinking random things for a few hours.)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">I could tell something must have gone wrong. The last stretches of the highway leading up to Tai Lam Tunnel — including the 3.8-kilometer tunnel itself — were brought to a complete standstill.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Trust Your Gut</title><link href="https://kathy.life/2019/07/26/trust-your-gut.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Trust Your Gut" /><published>2019-07-26T14:04:21+08:00</published><updated>2019-07-26T14:04:21+08:00</updated><id>https://kathy.life/2019/07/26/trust-your-gut</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://kathy.life/2019/07/26/trust-your-gut.html">&lt;p&gt;In the tail end of 2018, I built a prototype for a robot photographer. The goal was for it to one day serve as a photographer’s stunt double, so that photojournalists won’t always have to put &lt;em&gt;themselves&lt;/em&gt; in danger’s way in chaotic zones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The further vision was to repurpose the robot to assist in search and rescue missions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/GVRT2KngzvY&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/GVRT2KngzvY&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advisors: “Our city is a very peaceful place. No one’s ever gonna need your product here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I also built a rescue app. It’s a modernized emergency dispatch system for cases where 999 (911 in the US) calls are just not feasible. The app is blockchain-powered, which means it’s fast and more secure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/5Cj03FGo358&quot;&gt;https://youtu.be/5Cj03FGo358&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advisors: “Why would I need this when I could just call 999?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Such negative, old-fashioned feedback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did I let that stop me from building things? No, I just stopped listening to “advisors.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The moral of the story is that it’s OK to trust our gut instincts and build whatever we believe are worth building. If nothing else, the experience alone is priceless.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Kathy Li</name></author><summary type="html">In the tail end of 2018, I built a prototype for a robot photographer. The goal was for it to one day serve as a photographer’s stunt double, so that photojournalists won’t always have to put themselves in danger’s way in chaotic zones.</summary></entry></feed>